Dhimitër Gëro

Rr. Lidhja e Prizrenit, Tirana, AL 1001 +355 69 430 3737 | dhimitergero@gmail.com

PROFILE

Financial Consultant working in Consultancy Services for *more than 4 years*. Integrated background in *Accounting and Finance* with multi-faceted experience in diverse industries. *Digital Enthusiast* interested in new technologies, with a recent focus on learning *Python*. Seeking challenges with a disruptive focus on Finance and Business Transformation. Always committed to self-improvement, results—oriented mindset and highly curious about new business frontiers. Proactive

and supportive toward colleagues. Business proficiency in English and Italian.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Management Associate (6 months contract)

AON Plc – Commercial Risk Global Claims Dept.

Chicago, Illinois Aug 2021 – Feb 2022

- Support the Commercial Risk Global claims Dept. with process improvements, data analysis and manipulation, reporting.
- Involved within a special migration project called 'Claims Resolution Platform' while assisting project managers with data migration activities and change request management with external vendor.
- Coordinate and manage communication with global Aon country leaders regarding specific country related claim system requirments.

Financial Data Engineer

Cardo AI – Securitization Project

Tirana, Albania Aug 2020 – Aug 2021

- Support a portfolio of 6 SPV, more than 500 ths loans for a total of 1 billion EUR in outstanding balances (SME loan, Public Administration Contracts, Trade Receivables).
- Analysis and treatment of raw data to re-arrange them into robust and structured financial models, tailored for each client.
- Responsible for monitoring a team of three developers (Backend & Frontend), ensure accuracy and testing before client deliveries.
- Create detailed business analysis and proposing functional solutions with an eye on technical opportunities and business requests.

Financial Advisory Services Associate

Deloitte Albania & Kosovo – M&A Project Dept.

Tirana, Albania Nov 2019 – Jun 2020

- Performed in-depth analysis of Target's Financial Statements, with the final focus on generating the right acquisition price of the Target entity (EBITDA adjustment, PPE valuation, Net Debt calculation).
- Partnered with Deloitte Italy FAS Department to assist on their projects of Financial Due Diligences and prepare financial summaries of businesses historical performance.
- Prepared both Seller/Buyer Side Pitch Deck presentation for various projects in industry such as: Public Utilities, Manufacturing, Fashion.

Business Analyst

Adler Consulting – Business Development Dept.

Jan – Nov 2019

Tirana, Albania

- Performed financial forecasting models (Three Statement model, DCF, Budget) for domestic and Italian companies with the final focus to facilitate their internal and external business efforts.
- Assisted foreign companies with business plan preparation, pitch deck presentation, and domestic market research for relocation and/or expansion purposes.
- Facilitated and obtained SME grants/funding resources (max 100 thsd EUR) for business enlargement and/or financing operations.

Audit AssociateTirana, AlbaniaMazars Albania & Kosovo – Audit Dept.Oct 2017 – Nov 2018

- Performed general and specific controls to determine the accuracy and completeness of Clients Financial Statements, following National and International Audit Standards.
- Tested and analyzed audit cycles by implementing tailored strategies for each cycle, in coherence with National and International Financial Reporting standards.

Dhimitër Gëro

Rr. Lidhja e Prizrenit, Tirana, AL 1001 +355 69 430 3737 | dhimitergero@gmail.com

· Reported findings and misstatements regarding operational and administrative processes of companies workflow.

Local Governance Expert

Friedrich Ebert Stiftung, Tirana Office

Tirana, Albania Feb 2015 – Jan 2020

- Trained more than 200 students about Local Governance structures and relationships between Citizens Local Public Administration.
- Promoted and scheduled meetings/seminars between local governance stakeholders in more than 10 cities.
- Responsible for budget and expense administration of training held and reporting to the main office.

EDUCATION

Python 360 Certificate

eCornell, Cornell University, New York

Ongoing

Master of Science in Finance

The University of Tirana, Faculty of Economics, Tirana

2016 - 2018

Bachelor of Science in Accounting and Finance

The University of Tirana, Faculty of Economics, Tirana

2013 - 2016

AFFILIATIONS, PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, AWARDS

- Founder of "Urbana", an online platform that renders on-demand, location-based physiotherapy massages. (www.urbana.al)
- Initial contributor in forming "Junior Achievement Albania Alumni" and present member.
- · Co-founder of ODAY- Open Doors for Albania Youth, an organization focused on empowering youths.

SOFTWARE COMPETENCIES

- Proficient with Microsoft Office Suite
- Basic Knowledge of Python (+30 Verified Learning Hours)
- Normal User of PROFIS Invoice Cycle Italian Accounting Software